

Baikov Alexey

02.01.1987 (35 years)

Python backend developer

Level: Junior, Junior+ Employment: full time

Work schedule: remote working, full day

Salary expectations: \$1300

Contacts

- +7 (929) 053-73-35
- https://t.me/alexbaikov
- alex@baikov.dev
- https://github.com/baikov
- Nizhny Novgorod, Russia

Objectives

Start a career as a backend developer in a modern product company. Professional growth to the Middle level within a year and, as a result, an increase in my profitability. Stack: Python 3.6+, Django 2.2+, PostgreSQL, DRF, FastAPI, Docker.

Work Experience

february 2021 − present (1 year)

Learning new stack

I applied all the studied technologies in practice (project allflags.ru)

A short list of practical skills:

- · VPS administration, work with Heroku, AWS, Yandex.Cloud;
- · Configuring Nginx, Traefik, Prometheus, Grafana;
- · Working with Docker and Docker Compose, basics of CI/CD;
- · Codestyle (flake8, black), testing (pytest, coverage), documenting (Sphinx);
- · Working with version control and workflows (git, github, git-flow, github-flow);
- · Working with Django, DRF, PostgreSQL, Redis, Celery, Flower.
- october 2015 present (6 years 4 months)

PKF Luidor, Nizhny Novgorod (Car factory / special vehicles)

Web developer, SEO specialist

- Developed a service for finding spare parts by VIN (backend: Django/DRF, frontend: Vue.js);
- Development and SEO of the company's websites on 1C-Bitrix;
- More than 3 years of experience in remote work.
- april 2012 october 2015 (3 years 7 months)

Freelance, own projects

Full-stack developer, SEO specialist

- Website development and SEO (Joomla, WordPress, 1C-Bitrix, OpenCart).

Redox, Moscow (commerce / health products)

Product Manager

Redox, Nizhny Novgorod (retail / health products)

Sales Manager

■ november 2006 — may 2008 (1 year 7 months)

Telma Soft, Nizhny Novgorod (software development)

Trainee engineer in the software development and testing department

• Internship while studying at the university

About

I love web development. More than 10 years of experience in website development and SEO helped me to acquire skills in frontend, backend, DevOps and project managment. New technologies fuel my desire to learn more and more each day. I try to keep my code as clean as possible, following established standards for the technology I'm using at the moment.

Education

LOBACHEVSKY SUNN

Lobachevsky State University of Nizhny Novgorod

a 2004-2009 (5 years), full time, specialist

Faculty of Computational Mathematics and Cybernetics

Specialty: Applied Mathematics and Informatics

Qualification: mathematician, system programmer

Навыки



Languages

Russian Native
English Intermediate

Courses

Docker | 2021, slurm.io

Build a Backend REST API with Python & Django | 2021, Udemi

Algorithms and Data Structures in Python 3 | 2021, YouTube

Projects

Country flags

Search parts by VIN

ø parts.baikov.dev
 □ baikov/autoparts

Books

Python Tricks, Dan Bader
Grokking Algorithms, Aditya Bhargava
Practices of the Python Pro, Dane Hillard
Django 3.0. The practice of developing
websites in python, Dronov V. A.